Guide to the Bob Johnson Papers, 1949-2003 CTC.2014.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Bob Johnson Papers
1949-2003
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Johnson, Robert
CTC.2014.03
17 Linear Feet (15 boxes)
The Bob Johnson Papers contain paper based, photographic, and audio-visual materials related to the Brooklyn born, Pittsburgh-based, dancer/choreographer, actor and director. Johnson founded the Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble and served as a dance and drama lecturer at the University of Pittsburgh. Additionally, Robert Johnson toured internationally as a dancer and participated in a number of local, Broadway, and Off-Broadway productions as an actor, choreographer, and director.
Arrangement
The Bob Johnson Papers are arranged into the following series:
I. Personal Material, 1949-1992
II. Stephanie Johnson, ca. 1950- 2003
III. Journals/Notebooks, ca.1960-1986
IV. Artistic and Professional Career, 1956-1996
V. Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble, 1970-1985
VI. Teaching at the University of Pittsburgh, 1969-1986
VII. Black Arts Movement Scripts and Ephemera, 1966-1990
VIII. Audio/Visual Recordings, 1969-1985
Biography
Robert "Bob" Johnson was born on March 31, 1938 in Brooklyn, New York, to Viola Sutton and Fredrick Johnson. He received his foundational dance training at the New York Metropolitan High School of the Performing Arts (now LaGuardia High School of Music & Art and Performing Arts). Johnson began his professional career in 1960 as a member of the Eleo Pomare and Raymond Sawyer Dance Company. During this time, he continued his formal study of dance at a number of New York-based studios. On scholarships, Johnson studied dance composition, Hattian and Afro-Caribbean under Jean-Léon Destiné at the New Dance Group Studio, the Lector Horton Technique at the Clark Center of the Performing Arts, and the Katherine Dunham Technique under Ms. Dunham herself.
In 1965, Johnson traveled to Paris as part of Katherine Dunham's last professional company and took part in the French movie musical Deux Anges Sont Venus and the film adaptation of Léopold Sédar Senghor's Chaka. Upon returning to the United States in 1966, Mr. Johnson took dance instructor positions in Washington, D.C. and New York City. In this same year he made his acting debut as the lead in Kelly Marie Berry's dance drama, Black Happenin'. In 1967, Bob Johnson appeared in the N.Y. Shakespeare Festival original production of Hair. This was quickly followed by a dramatic role in Ed Bullins' Off-Broadway production,Goin' a Buffallo. Between 1968 and 1969 he returned to his dance background with stints with the Harlem Cultural Council's Dancemobile.
In 1969, Bob Johnson relocated to Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, to serve as a dance consultant for Project Self Esteem, a collaboration between local universities and youth groups. Members of the University of Pittsburgh's Black Studies Department took notice of Johnson in this role and offered him a position teaching both dance and drama in the department starting in the 1970-1971 school year. He accepted the post and remained in the department until his death in 1986. His courses included Afro American Dance I and II and Kuumba Theatre Workshop, later renamed Creativity Workshop. It was also in Pittsburgh where he met and married his wife, the former Stephanie Cooper.
In 1970, Bob Johnson founded the Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble which aimed to shed light on the breadth of culture in the African Diaspora to bring attention to issues facing the community through dance. Johnson served as artistic director of the company for a number of years during which time he choreographed signature works such as Free Spirit Song, Ritual of Damballah, Ego Trippin' and American Fruit with African Roots. Outside of the university and the dance company he founded, Mr. Johnson continued to work professionally as a dancer, choreographer, actor and director. During the summer months, Johnson toured nationally and internationally as a Dancer with Sun Ra and His Arkestra, performing in such places as Nigeria, Italy, France, and the Netherlands. As a choreographer, he crafted dance numbers for local productions such as the musical Liberty Avenue, and Off-Broadway Plays including Who Loves the Dancer by Rob Penny and How do you Spell Watergait by James Durrah. He continued to pursue local stage work and made his film debut in the John Russo horror film Midnight. Johnson would also go on to direct theater, notably the first staged production of August Wilson's Jitney in 1982.
Bob Johnson passed away due to heart failure on July 6, 1986.
Scope and Content Notes
The Bob Johnson Papers date from Johnson's late teens and early twenties in 1950s and 1960s (New York City) through his death in Pittsburgh in 1986. The collection is comprised of personal and professional letters, writings, contracts, scripts, theatre ephemera, and choreographic and artistic notes/illustrations. Further, the Johnson Papers contain photographic and A/V items, press clippings, material related to the Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble, material related to his tenure as a lecturer at the University of Pittsburgh, and the papers of his widow, the late Stephanie Cooper Johnson. The collection is broken into eight series and a number of subseries and sections. For the most part, each subseries' or section's folders are listed in chronological order.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Johnson Estate: Marimba Johnson Bright (daughter) and Samba Johnson (son) in December 2014.
Related Material
The Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Pittsburgh Performing Arts Information Files, CTC.Infofiles.Pgh, Curtis Theatre Collection, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Access and Use
In compliance with FERPA regulations, the following material has restricted access: Series VI: Teaching at the University of Pittsburgh: Subseries 3: Classes: Section: Student Work. To access material in this series the researcher must agree to sign a confidentiality agreement provided by Archives & Special Collections. All remaining portions of the collection are free of restrictions.
General
The processing of the audio/visual media in this collection was supported by a Recordings at Risk grant from the Council on Library and Information Resources. The grant program is made possible by funding from The Andrew W. Mellon Foundation.
Performing arts -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Black Arts movement; Dance -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Faculty papers; Personal papers; Choreographers -- United States; Modern dance -- United States -- History -- 20th century; African American dance -- History -- 20th century; African American dance; Dance -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Penny, Rob; Wilson, August; Johnson, Stephanie; University of Pittsburgh. Department of Black Community Education, Research and Development; Dunham, Katherine; Kuntu Repertory Theatre; Johnson, Robert
- Personal Material, 1949-1992; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains personal material related to Bob Johnson over the course of his life. Items in the series include a selection of awards and personal effects from his youth and artistic career, personal correspondence and topical material related to racial justice and the arts. This series also contains items related to Mr. Johnson's 1986 death and memorial services, and over 30 years of personal photographs.
  - Effects and Awards, 1949-1992; 1.
    - Autograph Book, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Slang Book (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Frederick Johnson, Veterans Administration Documents, August 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Photo Album, ca. 1955-1965 (Box 15)
    - French Work Permit, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Clippings Collage (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Poetry art collage (Oversize), ca. 1970 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 2)
    - Passport, 1971-1976 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Harvard Summer School, Arts Administrative Certificate, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - FESTAC ID, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Poster, FESTAC (Oversize), 1977 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 1)
    - Personal Letterhead (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Bicentennial Commission of Pennsylvania Appreciation Award, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - House of the Crossroads Appreciation Award, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. Commemorative Coalition Award, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Jimmy Hendrix Art Print by D. Jevsevar (Oversized) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Poster, Don't Call Me Man featuring the Howard Moore Ensemble (Oversized), November 1975 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Topical Files, 1966-1985; 2.
    - Africa Today v.17 no.4, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - African Nationalist Pioneer Movement Newsletters, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Amiri Baraka's Comments on Resignation of Haki Madhubuti and Jitu Weusi, May 24, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Anti-Apartheid Publications, 1969-1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Black Dialogue Magazine v.4 no.2, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Black News v.1 no.34 and v.2 no.10, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - The Black Scholar v.1 no.1, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Black Solidarity Fair program, May 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Galley Proof,Island Possessed by Katherine Dunham, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Institute of the Black World, 1971-1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - NDTC Newsletter XI (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, Neighborhood Arts Center booklets 2-4 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Persad Center, Board of Directors, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Proposed Statement of Principles and Charter for a National Black Independent Political Party, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Racial Justice in Broadcasting (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Sun Ra, 1969-1979 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Talk: The Family Magazine, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - United States Political Involvement in Angola and South Africa, 1976-1985 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - The Universal Messengers: Revolution Poems by Hassan Ali, Keito, Mahade Mohammed Ahmed, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Posters, Black political activism (Oversize), ca. 1968-1982 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 3)
    - Posters, Black Arts Movement (Oversize), ca. 1968-1982 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 3)
    - Posters, Black political activism Pittsburgh (Oversize), ca. 1970-1982 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 3)
    - Posters, Black Arts Movement Pittsburgh (Oversize), ca. 1970-1982 (Map-case 25-6, Oversize 3)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1986; 3.
    - Maisha Baton, ca.1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 32-38)
    - Maisha Baton, Photograph for Birthday (Oversized), 1978 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Felecia Bell, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Bill, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Glenn Brooks, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Walter Campbell, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Dan (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - David, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Chuck Davis (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Eddy, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - EST Training, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - L.D. Fraiser, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Marcella Galbusera, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Gail Gibson (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Janet Gillespie, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Vivian Graham (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Veronica Henderson (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Karen Holmes, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Phyllis Hyman (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Joan, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Byron Johns, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Fredrick Johnson (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Gwendolyn Kayser, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Lamont (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Howard S. Lucus, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Michelle Macau, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Mary, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Maja Milenivić, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Maliki Rucker, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Otis Sallid, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Raymond Sawyer, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Sheri (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Ed Smith, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Richard Smith, ca. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Maxine Strawder, 1971-1985 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Meredith Stuart, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Suliman, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Gilbert Sutton, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Teddy, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Delores Vanisop, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Leslie Warner (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Mautez V. Wilson (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Second World African Festival of Arts and Culture (FESTAC) Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Unknown, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Greeting Cards and Post Cards, 1965-1973 (Box 1, Folder 81-82)
    - "Get Well Soon" Cards, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Obituaries and Memorials, 1986-1989; 4.
    - Memorial Programs, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Concert Planning, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Concert Flyer, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Concert Ticket, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Bob Johnson Memorial Fund Donation Slip, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Thank You Letters, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Black Studies Newsletter v.1 no.3: Bob Johnson Dedication, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Poem: For Bob Johnson by August Wilson, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - In Memory of My Father by Marimba Johnson (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - African Heritage Classroom Committee Tribute to Bob Johnson (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - My Buddy Notes v. 2, no. 4/5: "In Memory of My Father" by Marimba Johnson, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - To BJ by Sandra Sowell-Scott, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Program: Salute to the Arts, VII A Sacred Service Honoring Deceased Minority Artists and Celebrating The Afro-American Contribution to the Performing and Visual Arts, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - My Buddy Notes v.3 no.8, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Press, Robert Johnson Passing, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Photographs, 1958-1986; 5.
    - Unidentified Woman by Coca-Cola Machine, December 1958 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Johnson Beach Candid, September 1959 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Young Johnson and Friends, Slides, ca. 1959-1964 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - New York City Candids, ca. 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - New York City Candids, Negatives, ca. 1959-1960s (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Beach Color Candids, Negatives, ca. 1960s (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Nightclub Performance, Negatives, ca. 1960s (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified Negatives, ca. 1960s (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Forest Candids, July 1963 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - New York City Subway Drummer, ca. 1960s (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Freda Vanterpool (Oversized), ca. 1960s (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Washington D.C. and New York City Candids, Slides, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Urban Landscapes and Candids, ca. 1970s (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
    - Concert, Beach, and Meeting Candids, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 14-15)
    - Candid Portraits, September 1972 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Pittsburgh City Scenes and Children, ca. 1970s (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Maisha Baton (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
    - Friends and Family Candids, ca. 1970s (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Color Candids, Slides, 1971-1978 (Box 11, Folder 21-34)
    - Black and White Beach Shots, ca. 1970s (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Johnson Candids with Unidentified Man (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Candid Friends and Family, ca. 1970s (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Unidentified Women with Silk Scarf (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Unidentified Family and Friends, Black and White and Color Negatives, ca. 1970s (Box 11, Folder 39-40)
    - Los Angeles Trip, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Eden, Nigerian Pen Pal, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Marimba and Samba Johnson, ca. 1970s (Box 11, Folder 43-44)
    - Wrapped in the Flag (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Portraits of Bob Johnson (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Bob Johnson with Dancers at Creek (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Three Rivers Stadium and Pittsburgh Skyline, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - McCurdy Arts Complex "Fete" Invitation with Photograph, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Unidentified Candids and Portraits (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Unidentified Man, Photograph and Negatives, ca. 1970s (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Family and Friends, Color Negatives, ca. 1970s (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Portrait of Raymond Sawyer (Oversize), ca. 1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified and Miscellaneous Photographs, ca. 1970-1986 (Box 13, Folder 1-26)
    - Unidentified and Miscellaneous Photographs (Oversized), ca. 1970-1986 (Box 14, Folder 6-8)
- Stephanie Johnson, ca. 1950- 2003; II.
  Biography
  Stephanie Cooper Johnson was born November 10, 1948 in McKeesport, Pennsylvania, to Samuel and Ernestine Davis Cooper. Mrs. Johnson graduated from McKeesport High School and later went on to attend the University of Pittsburgh. At Pitt she earned both her B.S. and Masters of Library and Information Science. She then worked for many years as the children's librarian at both the Homewood and Wilkinsburg libraries.
  Mrs. Johnson was deeply involved in her community and active in a number of organizations. She served as a committee member of Pittsburgh Ward 4, an officer with the University of Pittsburgh African American Alumni Council, member of the Alumnae Association, and Afro-American History Society. Mrs. Johnson's deepest and most sustained involvement was with the Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble, founded by her late husband Bob Johnson. Stephanie Johnson was instrumental in orchestrating the company's revival in the early 2000s.
  Items in this series relate to activities in Stephanie Johnson's community work and personal life, her work with the Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble and its revival, as well as her time as an officer with the University of Pittsburgh's African American Alumni Council
  - Personal, 1983-2003; 1.
    - Correspondence: Sonya Cooper (Sister), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Kimberly C. Ellis (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Yvonne, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Mother's Day Card (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Press Clippings, Samba Johnson, ca. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Press Clippings, Stephanie Johnson, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Press Clippings, Finishing and Modeling School, ca.1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - African Heritage Classroom Committee: A Tribute to a Living Elder, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - African Heritage Classroom: Book of Honor, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Cooper Golden Wedding Anniversary Announcement, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Black League for African American Culture, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Certificate of Election to Democratic County Committee, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Memorial Poem for Johnson by Dennis Brutus, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Program, DanceAfrica with Chuck Davis Autograph, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Press Clippings, August Wilson, 1999-2003 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - August Wilson Programs with Autographs, 1987-1999 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Pitt Magazine Articles, 1993-1999 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble Revival, 1970-2003; 2.
    - 'The Artist, The Art, and the Ensemble' Grant Proposal, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Grant Proposal Notes, 1996-2000 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Grant Supporting Documents, 1970-1986 (Box 2, Folder 20-29)
    - Administration and Correspondence, ca. 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Dancer Biographies (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Copyright Registration Procedures (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Company Ephemera, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Company Press, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Posters (Oversized), 2003 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - University of Pittsburgh African American Alumni Association, 1996-2003; 3.
    - Stephanie Johnson Biography in Pitt Alumni Association Annual Report, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - 100 Pitt African American Women Pioneers, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Homecoming Program and newspaper clipping, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Strategic Planning, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Planning, 1996-2002 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, Ken Green, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - County Proclamation, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - African American Alumni Council Newsletters, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Homecoming, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Meeting Notes and Planning, 1996-2002 (Box 2, Folder 44-45)
    - Homecoming Program, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Council Roster, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence, Mark A. Nordenberg, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Blue, Gold & Black: Chancellor Mark A. Nordenberg Reports on the Pitt African American Experience, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Homecoming Program, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Events, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Photographs, ca.1950-1987; 4.
    - Childhood Candids, ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Teen Years, ca. 1960s (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Modeling, ca. 1969 (Box 11, Folder 55-56)
    - Candids, ca. 1975-1980 (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - August Wilson at Various Events, ca. 1987 (Box 11, Folder 58)
- Journals/Notebooks, ca.1960-1986; III.
  This series is made up of a number of Bob Johnson's personal journals and notebooks. They contain handwritten entries on numerous topics including poetry, dance, teaching, acting, politics, and daily observations. Taken as a whole, they serve as a unique insight into the creative mind of Mr. Johnson. These journals and notebooks were rarely dated or titled. The titles and arrangement were impossed by the archivists.
  - Dance Sketches, 1. (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Black Dance Notes, 2. (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Black Dance, Poetry, Media, 3. (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - The Importance of Concert Dance, Eleo Pomare, Poetry, 4. (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - African American Dancers and Racism, 5. (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Dance Machine Skit, 6. (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Kuumba Workshop, 7. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Childhood, Dance Forms, 8. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Choreographers Comment Draft, Black Dance Companies, Chuck Davis Poem, 9. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Freddie from Haiti, 10. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Teaching Notes, 11. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Production Notes, 12. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Professional Notes - KRAAL, Jamaica, 13. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Script, Reading Notes, Attendance, 14. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dance Education Philosophy, 15. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Teaching, 16. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Production, 17. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Production, Education Philosophy, 18. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Teaching Philosophy, Directing, 19. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Dance Technique, 20. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Letters, Black Dance, 21. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Teaching, Dance in Nigeria, 22. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Lyrics/ Dialogue, 6 Week Workshop, 23. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Production, 24. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Productions, Teaching Philosophy, 25. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Kuumba Workshop, Contacts, 26. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Proposal Drafts, Roller Skating, Dance, 27. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Move to Pittsburgh, Black Studies Department, 28. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Letter of Rec., Black Poetry Event Proposal, 29. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Production Proposals, Professional Dossier, 30. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Press Party List, 31. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Lyrics, 32. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Trilogy Workshop, PBTDE, 33. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Contacts in Dance and Theater, Teaching, 34. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Theatre Urge Press Release, Productions, Nigeria, 35. (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Production, Lyrics, To Do, 36. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Jitney, Halloween Project, Kuumba, ca.1960-1985; 37. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Contacts, Black Conference of Higher Edu., 38. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Productions, Kuumba, Tenure Request, 39. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Script Drafts, Memoir and Professional Narrative, 40. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - MFA Program, Kuumba, 41. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Professional Bio, Dance, 42. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Ideas for "Love Duet", Productions, 43. (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Direction, Expenses, 44. (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Department Goals, Teaching, 45. (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Production, Lyrics, Dance Improv, 46. (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Production, Direction, 47. (Box 3, Folder 41)